Guide to the Robert J. Smith papers, 1950-2005.
Smith, Robert J. Papers, 1950-2005
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert J. Smith papers, 1950-2005
14-25-3175
Robert J. Smith, 1927-
43.5 cubit ft.
Correspondence, research, articles, course materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, research, articles, course material and lectures pertaining to Dr. Smith's study of Japan.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Anthropology and Asian Studies, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes articles and information about Japanese emperors, ancestor worship, the Japanese in Brazil, historical demography and material concerning the student protests at Cornell in 1969, correspondence with David Nathan Meyerson, and scrapbooks with newspaper clippings from World War I and World War II, material concerning Smith's participation in the Army Specialized Training Reserve Program and programs from various plays from the 1940s.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Smith, Robert John, 1927-; Cornell University--Faculty.; Army Specialized Training Program (U.S.); Wiswell, Ella Lury; Meyerson, David Nathan
Subjects:
Student movements--United States--History.; Students--Political activity.; Japanese--Brazil.; Emperors--Japan.; Ancestor worship--Japan.; Demography--Japan.; Japan--Study and teaching.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1914-1918.; Suye-Mura, Japan
Places:
Japan--Social life and customs.; Japan--Politics and government.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Slides (Photography).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Arranged by subject.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Boxes 1-8
Box 43 Folders 11, 13-19
Series II. Historical Demography (includes Data Card Sets)
Boxes 9-11
Series III. Course Material
Box 12
Box 22 Folders 3-6
Series IV. Committee Files, Awards
Box 13
Series V. Japanese Emperors
Box 14
Series VI. Morgan Lectures
Box 15
Series VII. Japanese in Brazil
Boxes 16-17
Box 43 Folder 9
Series VIII. Ancestor Worship
Boxes 18-19
Box 25 Folders 1-12
Series IX. Cornell 1969
Box 20
Series X. Reprints
Box 21
Series XI. Clippings -- Japan
Boxes 23-24
Box 26 Folders 1-16
Box 43 Folder 8
Series XII. Subject Files
Box 22 Folders 1-2, 7-16
Box 36 Folders 1-4
Series XIII. Calendars
Box 25
Series XIV. Book - Kurusu
Boxes 27-29
Box 36 Folders 18-19
Series XV. Scrapbooks
Boxes 30-32
Series XVI. Newspapers
Boxes 33-35
Series XVII. Army Specialized Training Reserve Program (ASTRP)
Box 37
Box 45
This material covers the years from Robert Smith's enlistment in the US Army Reserve in July 1944 to his service in the occupation of Japan in 1946. In the Army Specialized Training Reserve Program (ASTRP) and Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP) at Carnegie Tech, University of Minnesota and Yale University
Series XVIII. David Meyerson Material
Box 36
Series XIX. The W.W. Curtis Ainu Collection
Box 43 Folders 1-7
Series XX. Other Material
Boxes 37-38
Box 44
Series XXI. Suye-Mura Material
Boxes 46-47
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1-38)
    A-B
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1-49)
    C-Hanks
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1-51)
    H-K
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1-37)
    L - M
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1-42)
    N - Robertson, Jennifer
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1-40)
    Robertson, Jennifer - W
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 7, Folder 1-21)
    W-Z; Personal Libraries
  - Correspondence, 1960-2001 (Box 8, Folder 1-36)
    A-Z
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    A-E
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    F-H
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    K-L
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    M-O
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    P
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    R-T
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    W-Z
  - Correspondence, 1953-1997 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    Department of Anthropology
  - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    Royalties Statements
  - Correspondence, 1947-1952 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    Earl R. Miner
  - Correspondence, 1988-1997 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    East Asia Program Endowment
- Series II. Historical Demography
  - Data Card Sets
    - Horikoshi-Machl Lemochl (Box 9)
    - Hama-Issai-Cho, 1792-1861 (Box 9)
    - Hama-Issai-Cho, 1713-1788 (Box 9)
    - Hama-Kubo-Cho, 1819-1868 (Box 9)
    - Kubo-Machi Shakuya (Box 9)
    - Kubo-Machi Lemochi (Box 9)
    - Horikoshi-Machi-Shakuya (Box 10)
    - Hama-Kubo-Cho, 1771-1818 (Box 10)
    - Conference on Historical Demography, 1970s (Box 11)
    - Photographs-selected household registers (Box 11)
    - Notes and References (Box 11)
    - Conference paper and publications (Box 11)
- Series III. Course Material
  - Yale Univ. Anthropology Visiting Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Gardener Museum Symposium, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 9th World Congress of Sociology; Uppsala, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hume Lecture Yale University, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Univ. of Washington Distinguished Lecturer, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Holmberg/Sharp Dedication, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Oklahoma Symposium, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Japanese Village Restudy, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Rutgers Lecture, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Zagreb Conference, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - St. Michael's College Lecture, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Consortium Asian Studies, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Williams College Lectures, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - University of Rochester Visiting Committee, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Seminar: Japanese Society and Culture, 1981-1996 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Course Materials-Japanese Society, 1969-1996 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Children's Art (Japan) (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Asian Americans #1, 1986-1991 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Asian Americans #2, 1966-1987 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Urban Anthropology #1, 1970-1991 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Urban Anthropology #2, 1957-1991 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Urban Anthropology #3, 1964-1975 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Art and Culture #1, 1965-1971 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Art and Culture #2, 1963-1970 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Art and Culture #3, 1965-1970 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Art and Culture #4, 1952-1972 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1990 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Concept of Culture, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Hi No E Uma (Fire/Yang/Horse), 1966-1994 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Windows (Japan), 1972-1985 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Round, Cycle & Trajectory (Japan), 1965-1984 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Reflections on Japanese Society, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Retrospective View of Rural Community Studies (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Popular Religion In a Rural Community, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Study of Japan In the Social Sciences (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Finding a Voice for Japanese Village Women, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Asian American Experience, 1970-1977 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    # 1
  - Asian American Experience, 1940-1977 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    # 2
  - Asian American Experience, 1964-1975 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    # 3
  - Course: Japanese Society Student's Notebook, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Committee Files, Lectures and Awards
  - University of Hawaii Visiting Prof., 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Job Offers, 1961-1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Job Offers, 1959-1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Personal, 1968-1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Lectures, Reviews, Awards - 1
  - Miscellaneous Personal, 1965-1997 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    3
  - Annual Reports, 1963-64/1995-96 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Personal, 1974-1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Lectures, Reviews, Awards - 2
  - Memos, 1988-1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Miller Money (East Asia Program)
  - Association for Asian Studies-Distinguished Lecturer, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - CAU, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - CSU-Long Beach Anthropology Evaluation, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Univ. of Michigan Center for Japanese Studies, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Conference on the Role of Confucian Institutions, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Daedalus-Many Chinas, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Association for Asian Studies Regional, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Aspen/MIT Wye Woods, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Japan Political Economy Research Committee, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Japanese Spirituality (East-West Center), 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Development Process In Asia (East-West Center), 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Self and Society (East-West Center) #1, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Self and Society (East-West Center) #2, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Series V. Japanese Emperors
  - Imperial Family: General, 1971-1987 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Wedding of the Crown Prince, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Articles and Periodicals (Japanese) (Box 14)
  - Newspaper Articles (English) (Box 14)
- Series VI. Morgan Lectures
  - Lewis Henry Morgan Lectures, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Lewis Henry Morgan Lectures, 1963-1981 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Notes
  - Japanese Society, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Correspondence #1
  - Japanese Society, 1984-1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Correspondence #2
  - Japanese Society, 1988-2001 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Correspondence #3
  - Japanese Society, 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Reviews
  - Japanese Society, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Translation (Japanese)
  - Comparative Study of Technological Change (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Seminar In Technological Change, Minutes and Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 15, Folder Bound report)
  - Turning Leaves: Japanese American Family Albums, 1984-1995 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - NY Council-Asian Studies, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Club of New York, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Harvard, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    #1
  - Harvard, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    #2
  - Separate folder-Harvard (Box 15)
  - Harvard, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    #3
  - Harvard, 1983-1990 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    #4
  - Harvard, 1988-1990 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    #5
- Series VII. The Japanese in Brazil
  - Brazil - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Brazil - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Brazil - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Brazil - Correspondence, 1970-1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - *Unmarked folder (Box 16, Folder *5)
  - Maps #1 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Maps #2 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript, 1969-1983 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Religions (Draft)
  - Manuscripts (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Buddhism
  - Manuscripts (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Getulina Report
  - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Exodus
  - Manuscripts (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Acculturation & Assimilation
  - Manuscript, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Biculturalism
  - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Japanese Immigrants
  - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Kitaoji
  - Bibliography Notes, 1965-1979 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Visit of the Crown Prince and Princess, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers (Box 17)
  - Brazil Field Notes, 1966-67 (Box 43, Folder 9)
- Series VIII. Ancestor Worship
  - Ancestor Worship in Contemporary Japan, First Draft (Box 18)
  - Ancestor Worship In Contemporary Japan, As Submitted to Press (Box 18)
  - Stanford University Press, 1974-1971 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Correspondence
  - Ancestor Worship, 1974-1978 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Notes #1
  - Ancestor Worship (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Notes #2
  - Ancestor Worship, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Photographs
  - Correspondence-Maeyama/ACLS, 1969-1981 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Publicity, 1974-1983 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Ancestor Worship, Note Cards (Box 18)
  - Code Book, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Explanations (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Kin Terms and Charts (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Hyogo-Ken/Nara #071-081 /Shiga-Ken #001-014 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Yasuhara (Box 19, Folder 5)
    # 001-020
  - Nakayashiki, 1964-1974 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    #101-131 & Correspondence
  - Tokyo Katsushika-Ku (Box 19, Folder 7)
    #1-40
  - Tokyo Katsushika-Ku (Box 19, Folder 8)
    #41-80
  - Tokyo Katsushika-Ku (Box 19, Folder 9)
    #81-120
  - Tokyo Katsushika-Ku (Box 19, Folder 10)
    #122-148
  - General and Mitaka-Shi, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Osaka (Box 19, Folder 12)
    #001-065
  - Osaka (Box 19, Folder 13)
    #066-104
  - Kyoto (Box 19, Folder 14)
    #001-061
  - Sone (Box 19, Folder 15)
    #801-820
  - Sone (Box 19, Folder 16)
    #821-840
  - Sone (Box 19, Folder 17)
    #841-860
  - Sone (Box 19, Folder 18)
    #861-880
  - Sone (Box 19, Folder 19)
    #881-899
  - Sone, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    #801a-814a & Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 21)
    #901
  - Japanese Ancestor Worship, 1960s-1990s (Box 25, Folder 1-8)
  - Japanese Religious Life, - by Edward Putzar - text and slides, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 9-12)
- Series IX. Cornell - 1969
  - Anthropology Forum, May 1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Anthropological Ethics, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Cornell Daily Sun
  - Newspaper & Magazine Articles, Meeting Information, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper & Magazine Articles, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Memos, Newspaper Articles, Reports#1 1969, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Memos, Newspaper Articles, Reports #2, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Memos, Newspaper Articles, Newsletters #1, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Memos, Newspaper Articles, Newsletters #2, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Memos, Newspaper Articles, Newsletters, 1971-1975 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Newspapers-Cornell Daily Sun, 1976-1984 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Articles, Newsletters #1, 1969-1989 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Articles, Newsletters #2, 1969-1989 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Articles, Newsletters #3, 1969-1989 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Constituent Assembly (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Life Magazine (April 17 1970), Newspapers-Cornell Daily Sun, 1970-1972 (Box 20)
- Series X. Reprints
  - Reprints, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Reprints, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Reprints, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Reprints, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, 1962-1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - American Anthropological ASSOC Committee on Ethics, 1966-1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Ritual Change In East & Southeast Asia, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Family and Life Course, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Family and Life Course, 1981-1984 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Workshop on Gender (Japan), 1987 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Workshop on Gender (Japan), 1987 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - BEFU Workshop on Japanese Society, 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Japanese Family (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Kin Terms Study (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Kin Terms Study, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Kin Terms Study, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Kin Terms Study, 1962-1981 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Kinship Terms Study, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Kinship Terms Study (Box 21, Folder 21)
    #6 - Data Cards
- Series XI. Clippings
  - Japan Clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Japan Clippings, 1973-1989 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Japan Clippings, 1954-1985 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Japan Clippings, 1968-1983 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Japan Clippings, 1975-1983 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Japan Clippings, 1966-1995 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Japan Clippings, 1975-1990 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Crime
  - Japan Clippings, 1980-1989 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Other Crime, 1981-1997 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Japan Clippings, 1954-1989 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Architecture
  - Japan Clippings, 1977-1989 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Art
  - Japan Clippings, 1954-1989 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Japan Clippings, 1916-1981 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Japan Clippings, 1972-1984 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    Tourism
  - Japan Clippings, 1958-1996 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Japan Clippings, 1953-1988 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Theater and T.V.
  - Japan Clippings, 1958-1992 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Film
  - Japan Clippings, 1954-1989 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Japan Clippings, 1954-1989 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Music and Dance
  - Japan Clippings, 1954-1992 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Bunraku
  - Japan Clippings, 1958-1989 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    NOH
  - Japan Clippings, 1952-1982 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Kabuki
  - Japan Clippings, 1954-1989 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Japan Clippings, 1953-1989 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Gardens
  - Japan Clippings, 1946-1984 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Literature
  - Japan Clippings, 1968-1995 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    Mishima Yukio
  - Japan Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    Burakumin (Untouchables) # 1
  - Japan Clippings, 1983-1990 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    Burakumin (Untouchables) # 2
  - Japan Clippings, 1968-1994 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    Education/Youth
  - Japan Clippings, 1980s-90s (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
    Women
  - Japan Clippings, 1916-90s (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Marriage
  - Japan Clippings, 1960s-90s (Box 26, Folder 5-7)
    Religion
  - Japan Clippings, 1950s-90s (Box 26, Folder 8-11)
    Management
  - The Japan Times- 25,000th issue, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Ainu, 1970-1996 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - National Museum of Ethnology (Minpaku), 1980s (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Mura Hachibu - village ostracism, 1952-1961 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Japan - Rural Society, 1950s-90s (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Japan Newspaper Clippings, 1958-1968 (Box 43, Folder 8)
- Series XII. Subject Files
  - Workshop on Japanese City, 1974-1976 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Workshop on Japanese City, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Ogiya-Jusco Yasuda (Cornell Alum), 1994-1998 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Ogiya-Jusco Yasuda (Cornell Alum), 1993 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Japanese Villages, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Okayama TV
  - Shibutani Manuscript, 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Military Occupation of Japan
  - Shibutani Manuscript, 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Military Occupation of Japan (Continued)
  - Maps (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Magazine Photo Series, 1976-1985 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Magazine Photo Series, 1974-1976 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Magazine Photo Series, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Magazine Photo Series, 1972-1977 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Okoda Shigeru (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Time and Ethnology, 2000-2001 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Manuscript and correspondence
  - Theater slides (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
    Japan
  - Ehime-maru Incident (Hawaii 2001 ) (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Hanshin Earthquake ( 1995 )- published materials (Box 43, Folder 12)
- Series XIII. Calendars
  - Robert Smith's yearly calendars,1970-2001 (Box 25)
- Series XIV. Book - Kurusu
  - Field notes, 1950s (Box 27)
  - Stanford University Press, 1976-2001 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    correspondence/royalities statements
  - Stanford Press, 1978-1986 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Publicity
  - Stanford University Press, 1978-1982 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Kurusu, 1976-1982 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Translation
  - Kurusu, 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    Field notes - drafts
  - Kurusu, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Kurusu, 1951-1975 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Bibliography notes
  - Kurusu, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    Photographs (dissertation)
  - Kurusu and Kagawa (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
    Maps
  - Kagawa (Box 28, Folder 11)
    Pamphlets, ads, clippings
  - Miscellaneous catalogs (Box 28)
  - Kurusu (Box 29)
  - Kurusu and Kagawa, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 18-19)
    Pref - color slides
- Series XV. Scrapbooks
  - Newspaper clippings 1939-1944 (Box 30)
  - Newspaper clippings 1937-1944 (Box 31)
  - Newspaper clippings and playbills and programs @1940-1945 (Box 32)
    From various shows such as: Fantasia, Hamlet, Barnum and Bailey Circus, Macbeth, Porgy and Bess, Harvey, The North Star and Ice-Capades of 1944
- Series XVI. Newspapers
  - Copies of Mainichi and the Nippon Times concerning WW II, 1940s-1950s (Box 33-35)
- Series XVII. Army Specialized Training Reserve Program (ASTRP)
  These materials cover the years from Robert Smith's enlistment in the US Army Reserve in July 1944 to his service in the occupation of Japan in 1946. In the Army Specialized Training Reserve Program (ASTRP) and Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP) at Carnegie Tech, University of Minnesota and Yale University.
  - Prehistory and photograph of Language and Area Program at the University of Minnesota, October 1944 ,and color photo of the survivors and spouses at the same location, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Oral history of the ASTRP Japanese Language Class of 1944, 17 to 70- by James R. Price, 1944 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Japanese language lessons, 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 3-6)
  - Occupation of Japan - 25th Infantry Division - G-2 reports, 1946 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Reunions, surveys, directories and photographs, 1990s-2001 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter published by William Bridges - Gaya-gaya is the Japanese for "making a racket", 1988-2002 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Corrrespondence, 1988-1994 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1997-2002 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Personal/professional papers: miscellaneous posters, correspondence, manuscripts (finished and draft) (Box 45)
    Seventeen to Seventy: An Oral History of the ASTRP Japanese Class of 1944 - set of four audiotapes made in 1997 by James R. Price
    Vol. 1 (2 copies; original and revision): (Chapter I: Entry into the ASTRP Program, Chapter II: From Slide Rule to Green Tea, Chapter III: Minnesota Experience)
    Vol. 2: (Chapter IV: On to Basic Training, Chapter V: The Grand Finale at Yale, Chapter VI: In the Army (Japan and Elsewhere Parts 1 and 2))
  - Correspondence, 1997-2002 (Box 45)
- Series XVIII. David Nathan Meyerson Material
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan-June 1995 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, July-Dec 1995 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Jan-April 1996 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, May-Dec 1996 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan-May 1997 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, June-Dec 1997 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Jan-June 1998 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, July-Dec; David Meyerson died 10/17/98 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Publications - short story, screenplay, translation from the Japanese (Box 36, Folder 17)
- Series XIX. The W.W. Curtis Ainu Collection
  - Background and Notes on William Willis Curtis in Japan, 1877-1896 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - W.W. Curtis photographs (Japan) and Notes, 1877-1986 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Cataloging the Curtis Ainu Collection at Cornell, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Curtis Ainu Collection: photographs of the 50 items (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Curtis Ainu Collection: Exhibit at Hokkaido Kaitaku Kinenkan, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Curtis Ainu Collection: Complete set of photographs and Certificate acknowledging donation by RJS from the Director of the Hokkaido Kaitaku Kinenkan (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Ainu Project of the National Museum of Natural History (Smithsonian Institution) and Nagoya University (Box 43, Folder 7)
- Series XX. Other Material
  - Maps of Brazil from research project - in two large tubes, 1966-67 (Box 37-38)
  - Clippings (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Quotes: lecture materials (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Order of the Rising Sun materials I (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Order of the Rising Sun materials II (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Order of the Rising Sun materials III (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Personal files I (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Personal files II (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Personal files III (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Retirement Symposium I (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Retirement Symposium II (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Retirement Symposium III (Box 44, Folder 11)